Welcome to our overview of B2B Central.
If you're a new professional seller in the Amazon store
or new to selling to Amazon business customers, you might be looking for a better way to understand
and manage your business to business or B2B sales.
B2B Central can help you get started with
recommended actions and resources.
It can also help grow your business by providing insights
into your B2B sales.
You can find B2B Central by opening the Seller Central main menu,
hovering over B2B and clicking B2B Central.
You'll see a static menu,
widgets to help you get started, and a set of dashboards and reports.
Let's start by exploring the dashboards.
You can use each dashboard in B2B Central to view data
and generate graphs and tables for your B2B sales.
Click the dropdown menus in each dashboard to gain
insights into trends and turning points.
The sales snapshot lets you view and compare your B2B
and non-B2B sales.
Pull your data by number of sales or units sold and specify a date range.
Then review your results using the line graph at the top and table at the bottom of the dashboard.
You can also compare sales in your selected date range to your performance during the same time
last year.
Or you can review changes in your sales year over year.
We provide total sales for
both B2B and non-B2B transactions along with the number of customer orders, order items, and units
sold.
We use this information to provide a profile for an average order so you can see what a typical
business customer has been purchasing from you.
B2B performance by customer segment provides
insights into the types of business customers buying from you.
You can filter your sales using
three customer types, industry, region, or size.
Pick a customer type, choose to view your data by
number of sales or units sold, and specify a date range.
Then review your results using the
pie chart at the top and table at the bottom of the dashboard.
For example, see the difference
between your sales to commercial and education customers.
For each sub-segment, we provide your
sales year over year, your total sales, and an average order.
Top B2B products by customer
segment lists your best-selling products in descending order.
Pick the industry or industries
you want to track, view by number of sales or units sold, and specify your date range.
We provide
each product and your total sales and units sold.
You can also manage pricing, inventory, or images
for a product using the edit drop-down menu, or click advertise listings to create an Amazon ads
campaign.
Next to your B2B central dashboards, we provide access to a downloadable report.
B2B
quantity discount impact lets you see the effect your discounts have had on your sales and product
detail page views.
Compare the number of units sold, orders received for a given product, and the
percentage of times your products appeared as the featured offer.
In addition to your dashboards
and the B2B quantity discount impact report, B2B central houses a suite of resources and tools
for Amazon business sellers.
The static menu takes you to frequently visited pages.
Click
manage quotes to view and respond to requests from business customers who want to buy specific
products in bulk at a discount.
In some cases you may also see requests from business customers
for custom quotes.
Visit the B2B product opportunities page to explore weekly suggestions for B2B products.
We include products in high demand from categories you already sell in as well as products requested
by business customers that may not yet be available in the Amazon store.
Click business profile to
add a mission statement, logo, featured image, or other information to your public seller profile.
This can help showcase your company to business customers.
Looking for specific steps to get
started as a B2B seller?
Click grow B2B sales to get a list of actions you can take to encourage
sales from business customers.
Click business discount insights if you'd like help setting
business prices and quantity discounts for your products.
We provide a ranked list of 10 of your
products that could benefit from business pricing and offer both suggested prices and possible
quantity tiers.
You can also download a full list of products we're recommending business discounts
for.
If you have a brand enrolled in Amazon brand registry, click case pack recommendations to get
a list of single unit products you may be able to sell to business customers as case packs.
Review
a ranked list of suggested products that have been purchased in multi-unit orders along with our
recommended case pack sizes.
You'll also find widgets in the scrolling menu in B2B central that
suggest actions to help you get started with B2B sales.
Click icons to get tips, set prices and
discounts or automate business pricing.
You can explore B2B product recommendations, respond to
customer quote requests and update your business profile too.
We put all these resources in one
place to simplify and coordinate your business sales in Seller Central.
This concludes our B2B
central overview.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.